Dharmit Saradva

dsaradva@gmail.com | +91-9409678919 | Personal Portfolio

About

A DevOps Developer and an enthusiastic cloud solutions architect, with working experience of around 2 years in the DevOps and AWS architecting field. I have great experience with AWS services, GitLab CI/CD, and Linux systems. I am also familiar with other cloud service providers like IBM cloud, Oracle cloud infrastructure, and Microsoft Azure.

Experience

Solvative LLC Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Full Stack DevOps Engineer

July 2020 - Present

- Responsible for developing and maintaining DevOps workflows for various MERN stack projects.
- Familiar with AWS services used for Web applications and Mobile applications. Guiding developers towards AWS solutions and architectures.
- Managing high availability infrastructures and also I'm responsible to create AWS architectures for the projects.
- Worked with IaC tools like Ansible and CloudFormation. I've used CloudFormation for 2 tier VPC web project setup on AWS
 and had used Ansible playbooks for managing dependencies of LAMP stack and MERN stack projects.
- Having experience in shell scripts development for environment setup and SSL certificate management setup.
- I've also worked as a backend developer in the MERN stack project and developed REST APIs in Node.js

Peerbits Solutions Ltd. Ahmedabad, Gujarat

DevOps Trainee

December 2019 - April 2020

- Worked on the project deployment cycle
- Worked with the development team and took the responsibility of AWS resource management used in project development.
- Developed the AWS CodePipeline and BitBucket Pipeline for automating the code deployment process
- Worked on the infrastructure configuration management

Skills and Technologies

- AWS
- GitLab CI/CD
- Docker containerization
- Node.js (Intermediate)
- Python scripting

- Shell Scripting
- Linux
- Ansible
- Automation
- Jenkins

Education

Ganpat University

August 2016 - April 2020

- Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering with Specialization in Cloud-Based Applications
- Aggregate CGPA: 7.5

Awards & Certifications











A glimpse of work experience

- Multi-environment and dynamic port deployment pipeline using GitLab CI/CD: GitLab provides built-in CI/CD tools to automate the build, test, and deployment workflows.
 - The need for the multi-environment pipeline is to avoid the overlapping of code in a single environment; when multiple developers run pipelines on a particular environment at the same time, their code was being overlapped and only the latest pipeline was getting output.
 - To prevent this issue I've designed CI/CD in such a way that every job will get a unique port so their code won't get overlap in the same environments.
- Orchestration of the Docker containers with the docker-compose client: It was the IoT-based project having compatibility
 with Raspberry Pi devices. The main aim was to transform rigid infrastructure into containerized infrastructure.
 - o I've used Docker containers to transform traditional applications into the containerized application and used docker-compose clients to orchestrate the containers.
- **Peer-to-peer recognition system:** This is a product-based application that engages an internal peer-to-peer reward recognition system where fellow employees can show gratitude to their peers.
 - **o** This project was developed on the MERN stack, the backend was developed on Node.js. I worked on API creation to manage various events and features.
 - o I've also managed the customer and subscription management activities using Stripe service.
- 2 tier VPC resources setup with AWS CloudFormation: A web application project, in which database instance should be in private mode in order to provide basic security.
 - o I used the AWS CloudFormation tool to create and maintain resources in AWS. In that, I've created a couple of stacks for creating and launching network infrastructure and server infrastructure. In network infrastructure, a couple of subnets, internet gateway, and NAT gateway were created.
 - On the server-side, it created backend and database server, backend server was configured in public subnet with Elastic IP and database server was configured in a private subnet with allowing restricted access.
- **LAMP and MERN environment setup with** *Ansible* **and** *Shell script*: Ansible is a tool that allows Infrastructure-as-Code and managing underlying infrastructure using SSH protocol.
 - o I've created Ansible playbooks to set up MERN stack and LAMP stack environments. I've also created a shell script to install custom versions of the LAMP stack and MERN stack resources.